Guide to the Leonid Hurwicz papers, 1911-2008 and undated RL.00599
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1970-1980s, 22 boxes
  - First Alphabetical Subseries
    - NBER (National Bureau of Economic Research) (Box 13)
    - National Science Foundation, Folders 1-2 of 13 (Box 13)
    - National Science Foundation, Folders 3-13 of 13 (Box 14)
    - Nayak, Jayendra (Box 14)
    - Nayak, Vijay (Box 14)
    - Negishi, T. (Box 14)
    - Neymann, Abraham (Box 14)
    - Norhaus, William (Box 14)
    - Northwest Airlines (Box 14)
    - Ohio State University (Box 14)
    - Office of Research Administration (Box 14)
    - Okita, Saburo (Box 14)
    - Olson, Kathy (Box 14)
    - Oniki, Hajime (Box 14)
    - Osana, Hiroaki (Box 14)
    - Oskam, Arie (Box 14)
    - Oxford University Press (Box 14)
    - Page (Box 14)
    - Papandreou, A & M (Box 14)
    - Parking Services (Box 14)
    - Paulu (Box 14)
    - Pazner, Assaf (Box 14)
    - Pereira, Pedro Telhado (Box 14)
    - Perlman, Mark (Box 14)
    - Philosophy of Science (Box 14)
    - Plott, Charles (Box 14)
    - Pollak, Robert (Box 14)
    - Postlewaite, Andrew (Box 14)
    - Promotion and Tenure (Box 15)
    - Qin, Duo (Box 15)
    - Quirk, James P. (Box 15)
    - Rader, Trout (Box 15)
    - Radner, Roy (Box 15)
    - Rapp, Rip (Box 15)
    - Rashid, Salim (Box 15)
    - Reiter, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Report and Review Committee (Box 15)
    - Richter, Rolf (Box 15)
    - Roberts, John (Box 15)
    - Rosenthal, Robert W. (Box 15)
    - Runge (Box 15)
    - Rust, John (Box 15)
    - Rutherford, Aris (Box 15)
    - Ruttan, Vern, Folders 1-10 of 16 (Box 15)
    - Ruttan, Vernon, Folders 11-16 of 16 (Box 16)
    - Saijo, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Salmela, Ron, photographer (Box 16)
    - Samuelson, Larry (Box 16)
    - Sargeant, Thomas (Box 16)
    - Sato, Kimitoshi (Box 16)
    - Schmeidler, David (Box 16)
    - Schofield, Norman (Box 16)
    - Senate committee on Faculty Affairs, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Sermenev, A.M. (Box 16)
    - Shan, Feng (Box 16)
    - Shapiro, Leonard (Box 16)
    - Shapley, Lloyd (Box 16)
    - Shearin, Laura (Box 16)
    - Shell, Karl (Box 16)
    - Sher, William (Box 16)
    - Simler, J. (Box 16)
    - Simon, Carl (Box 16)
    - Single Quarter Leave (Box 16)
    - Sloan Funding Progress Report (Box 16)
    - Smith, Harlan (Box 16)
    - Smith, Vernon (Box 16)
    - Somit, Albert (Box 16)
    - Sonnenschein (Box 16)
    - Srinivasan (Box 16)
    - Stadler, Wolfram (Box 16)
    - Staff Assistance Office (Box 16)
    - Stanford, 1979 Summer (Box 16)
    - Stanford expenses, 1982 (Box 16)
    - Stassen Center, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Statistics Dept (Box 16)
    - Stern, Steve (Box 16)
    - Stigum, Bernt (Box 16)
    - Streufert, Peter (Box 16)
    - Sunder, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Super Computer (Box 17)
    - Swan, Craig (Box 17)
    - Symposium for PhD Centenary (Box 17)
    - Ullman-Margalit (Box 17)
    - Takayama (Box 17)
    - Tanaka, Kiyokazu (Box 17)
    - Tansel, Aysit (Box 17)
    - Teaching Evaluation (Box 17)
    - Teaching Schedule (Box 17)
    - Tenure - L.H. Vita (Box 17)
    - Testfasion, Leigh (Box 17)
    - Teubal, Morris (Box 17)
    - Thompson, Russell (Box 17)
    - Thomson, W. (Box 17)
    - Thore, Sten (Box 17)
    - Tian, Guogiang (Box 17)
    - Tideman, Nicholaus (Box 17)
    - Telephones (Box 17)
    - Tobin, James (Box 17)
    - Tauchen, Helen (Box 17)
    - Tower, Edward (Box 17)
    - Townsend, Robert (Box 17)
    - Traub, J.F. (Box 17)
    - Travel expenses (Box 17)
    - Travel, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Traub proposal (Box 17)
    - Travel - University of Minnesota policies (Box 17)
    - Trengualye, Pierre de (Box 17)
    - Trockel, Dr. Walter (Box 17)
    - Turner, John E. (Box 17)
    - Twin Cities Assembly, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Tyler, Ralph (Box 18)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box 18)
    - Univ. of Saskatchewan (Box 18)
    - UNIX proposal (Box 18)
    - Uppal, Jogindar (Box 18)
    - Upson, Roger (Box 18)
    - Uzawa, Japan Foundation Application (Box 18)
    - Vance bibliographies (Box 18)
    - Varian, Hal (Box 18)
    - Vega-Redondo, Fernando (Box 18)
    - Verba, Sidney (Box 18)
    - Vice President for Administration - Search Process (Box 18)
    - Vives, Xavier (Box 18)
    - Walker, Mark (Box 18)
    - Wallace, John (Box 18)
    - Walz, Susan (Box 18)
    - Wang, Hongshang (Box 18)
    - Warr, Peter (Box 18)
    - Washington State University (Box 18)
    - Watches Instruction (Box 18)
    - Waters, Lindsay (Box 18)
    - Watson, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Wayne State Conference (Box 18)
    - Weinberger, Hans (Box 18)
    - Weintraub, E. Roy (Box 18)
    - Weitstein, David (Box 18)
    - Weitzman, David (Box 18)
    - Wentworth, Donald (Box 18)
    - White, George (Box 18)
    - White Seminar, 1978 May (Box 18)
    - White, Susan (Box 18)
    - Who's Who (Box 18)
    - Who's Who in America (Box 18)
    - Williams, C. Arthur (Box 19)
    - Williams, Steve (Box 19)
    - Williamson, O.E. (Box 19)
    - Wilson, Library (Box 19)
    - Winter, Sidney (Box 19)
    - Wooders, Myrna (Box 19)
    - Woodward, James (Box 19)
    - World Affairs Center (Box 19)
    - W.W. Norton and Co. (Box 19)
    - Xu, Hau (Box 19)
    - Yannelis, N. (Box 19)
    - Yo, Gioseob (Box 19)
    - Yoshino, Hishiro (Box 19)
    - Young, S. (Box 19)
    - Youngdale (Box 19)
    - Yuen, Kwan Koo (Box 19)
    - Zaidi, M. (Box 19)
    - Zarnowitz, Victor (Box 19)
    - Zhao, Yaohui (Box 19)
    - Ziebarth, E. (Box 19)
    - Zajac, E.E. (Box 19)
  - Second Alphabetical Subseries
    - Abreu, D. (Box 19)
    - Akerlof, George (Box 19)
    - Ackley, Gardner (Box 19)
    - Agullar (Box 19)
    - Aizpurra (Box 19)
    - Aimes, Edward (Box 19)
    - Anderson, T.W. (Box 19)
    - Aumann, R. (Box 19)
    - Balasko, Yves (Box 19)
    - Baumol (Box 19)
    - Becker, William (Box 19)
    - Ben-Zion, Uri (Box 19)
    - Berger, Melvyn (Box 19)
    - Boston conference, 1980, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Brock, Horace (Box 19)
    - Brzeski, A. (Box 19)
    - Camacho (Box 19)
    - Calsamiglia (Box 19)
    - Chakravarty, Satya (Box 19)
    - Chandler P. (Box 19)
    - Charnes, A. (Box 19)
    - China (Box 19)
    - Cichoki (Box 19)
    - Cohen, Susan (Box 19)
    - Coifman, Virginia (Box 19)
    - Conn, David (Box 19)
    - Datta-Chandhuri, Mrrnal (Box 19)
    - Decentralization Conference, 1979 (Box 19)
    - Desai, Padma, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Dorfman, Robert (Box 19)
    - Douglas, Edna (Box 19)
    - Draghi, Mario (Box 19)
    - Dudkin, L.M. (Box 19)
    - Dybuig, P.H. (Box 19)
    - Ericson, Richard, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Erlich, Alex (Box 19)
    - Evan, William (Box 19)
    - Fand, D. (Box 20)
    - Feltenstein, Andrew (Box 20)
    - Feiwel, G. (Box 20)
    - Ferber, M. (Box 20)
    - Fisher, Frank (Box 20)
    - Flueckinger, Jerry (Box 20)
    - Fraser, Donald (Box 20)
    - Fromm, Gary (Box 20)
    - Gale, David (Box 20)
    - Gopalakrishna, Mallika (Box 20)
    - Gottinger, Hans (Box 20)
    - Griliches, Zvi (Box 20)
    - Guesnerie, Roger (Box 20)
    - Hamburger, Philip (Box 20)
    - Handler, Henry (Box 20)
    - Heal, Geoffrey, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Hechter, Oscar (Box 20)
    - Holmes, J. (Box 20)
    - Jordan, J.S. (Box 20)
    - Jorgenson, Dale W. (Box 20)
    - Kanemitsu, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Kareken, John (Box 20)
    - Klank, Bruno (Box 20)
    - Kornai, Janos (Box 20)
    - Krislov, Boyum Committee (Box 20)
    - Krueger, A.O. (Box 20)
    - Hurwicz commitment, Stanford, 1978 (Box 20)
    - Laffont, Jean-Jacques (Box 20)
    - Lange, Oskar Honorary Essay, 1963 (Box 20)
    - Lucas, Robert (Box 20)
    - Machlup, Fritz (Box 20)
    - Magill, Michael (Box 20)
    - Marshak, Jacob (Box 20)
    - Mas-Colell, Andreu (Box 20)
    - Masch, U. (Box 20)
    - Matsui, Yoshiki (Box 20)
    - Midwest Conf. On Mathematical Economics (Box 20)
    - Miesbauer, John (Box 20)
    - Mondale, Walter (Box 20)
    - Midwest Conference on Mathematical Economics (Box 20)
    - Miesbauer, John (Box 20)
    - Mondale, Walter F. (Box 20)
    - Mosco, Umberto (Box 21)
    - Murty, M.N. (Box 21)
    - National Academy of Science, 1981-1982 (Box 21)
    - Ne'eman, Yuval (Box 21)
    - Osann, Hirouki (Box 21)
    - Pazner, Elisha, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Pechman, Joseph (Box 21)
    - Philosophy, Colloquium (Box 21)
    - Pillamari, Leela (Box 21)
    - Plott Charles (Box 21)
    - Postlewaite, Andrew, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Premsirut, Ropchai (Box 21)
    - Public Choice, Journal (Box 21)
    - Quie, Al (Box 21)
    - Radio Listing (Box 21)
    - Radner, Roy (Box 21)
    - Roemer, John (Box 21)
    - Sertel, Murat (Box 21)
    - Senesh, Lawrence (Box 21)
    - Royalties (Box 21)
    - Ruttan (Box 21)
    - Saijo (Box 21)
    - Samuelson, Paul (on Hurwicz/Reiter and the Ville Theorem), 1979 (Box 21)
    - Schmeidler, David, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Shapiro, L. (Box 21)
    - Simon, Herb (Box 21)
    - Sondermann, Dieter (Box 21)
    - Spitzer (Box 21)
    - Springer (Box 21)
    - Smale, Stephen (Box 21)
    - Spanish publication (Box 21)
    - Stein, R. (Box 21)
    - Stiglitz, Joseph (Box 21)
    - Strotz, Robert (Box 21)
    - Stutzer, Mike (Box 21)
    - Tam, Mo-Yin (Box 22)
    - Tintner, G. (Box 22)
    - University Foundation (Box 22)
    - USSR Exchange (Box 22)
    - University of Arizona (Box 22)
    - Walker, Mark (Box 22)
    - Wang, Hongshang (Box 22)
    - Weintraub, E. Roy (Box 22)
    - Weitzman, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Welch, Robert L. (Box 22)
    - Williams, Steve, 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Wildasin, David (Box 22)
    - Yaari, M. (Box 22)
    - Yohe, Gary (Box 22)
    - Zeckhauser, Richard (Box 22)
  - Electronic correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 22)
    Approximately 46 folders of email correspondence (2008-0003), along with other account folders. NOTE: Email files must be screened by archivist before use.
    Conditions Governing Access note
    [Electronic records have been migrated to a library server. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
- Personal Files Series, 1930-2009, 3 boxes
  Series includes early letters, memorabilia, and other items documenting Hurwicz's migration to the U.S. from Poland and his early years in the U.S. (1939-1946); curriculum vitae; press clippings and articles; Nobel Prize memorabilia; and obituaries following his death in 2009. Languages include French and Polish. Included are documents from Hurwicz's early student years in Poland and at the London School of Economics, as well as early papers from his first positions in the U.S. Many of the letters written in Polish to Hurwicz in the early 1940s appear to be from his father and other family members, who, with Hurwicz's efforts, also emigrated to the U.S. after he had established himself in the U.S. Folders and their contents have been kept mostly in original order as filed by Hurwicz. Arranged alphabetically by folder title, with the correspondence in chronological order.
  - Abraham Hurwicz, death, 1981 (paper binder) (Box 23)
  - Academic records, 1930s-1940s (Box 23)
  - Academic records, emigration papers, and related documents, ca. 1934-1946 (Box 23)
  - Academic records, transcript, 1945 (Box 23)
    Scope and Contents
    Accession 2017-0054, received as a gift from Shomu Banerjee.
  - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Biographical: Clippings and papers, 1970s (Box 23)
  - Biographical: Memorial service, 2008 (Box 23)
  - Biographical: Obituaries, 2008 (2) (Box 23)
  - Biographical: Who's Who in the Midwest, 2006 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Nov. 21-1940 Sept. 1940 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Sept. 12-1940 Dec. 24 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1941 April 8-1945 Sept. 12 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1945 Sept. 17-1946 Feb. 13 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, Europe, 1948 Jan 29.-1948 Dec. 14 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Mar. 13-1950 July 2 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1953 Nov. 30-1974 Aug. 17, 1992, 1998, 2001 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 23)
  - Emigration documents, related memorabilia and papers, 1939-1946 and undated (Box 23)
  - Financial and related documents (in paper binder), 1940s-1980s (Box 23)
  - Memorabilia (papers, clippings) and vitae, 1945-1995 and undated (Box 23)
    Includes a few items from early years in the U.S.
  - McCarthy period inquiry into Hurwicz, 1951 (Box 24)
  - Messages to L. Hurwicz for the Nobel Prize, University of Minnesota, Friends and Colleagues, 2007 Oct. (Box 24)
  - Messages to L. Hurwicz for the Nobel Prize, University of Minnesota, Students and Alumni, 2007 Oct. (Box 24)
  - Clippings on National Medal of Science (1990) and Nobel (2007) (Box 24)
  - Printed materials, 1966, 1978 and undated (Box 24)
  - Printed materials, 1978, 1988 and undated (Box 24)
  - Publications log, 1985 (Box 24)
  - Reprints of Hurwicz articles, 1940s-1950s, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Univ. of Illinois resignation, 1949-1951 (Box 24)
    Clipping announcing Hurwicz appointment, 1949; two-page copy of resignation letter, 1951; several clippings giving context for resignation.
  - Vitae, 1991-2000, 4 folders (Box 24)
  - Hurwicz curriculum vitae, 1988-2000, 20 folders (Box 25)
- Printed Materials Series, 1940s-2000s and undated, 22 boxes
  Consists chiefly of reprints and working papers, generally bound printed materials with a few annotations. Hurwicz's reprints and working papers are arranged in chronological order. Printed materials by colleagues are arranged by alphabetical order of the first author's last name. Though these are mainly articles, they also include PhD dissertations, reports or memoranda which are arranged alphabetically by author's name or by the institution for which it was written. The series also contains a full box of various brochures (economics departments, conference programs) and a box filled with unidentified papers in Russian.
  - Hurwicz reprints
    - 1940s (Box 25)
    - 1950s (Box 25)
    - 1960s (Box 25)
    - 1970s (Box 25)
    - 1980s (Box 25)
    - 1990s-2000s (Box 25)
  - Hurwicz Working Papers
    - 1950s, with Kenneth Arrow (Box 26)
    - 1950s, Office of Naval Research, with K. Arrow (Box 26)
    - 1967, with Richter (Box 27)
    - 1970-1975, with Reiter and Radner (Box 27)
    - 1973-1976 (Box 27)
    - 1975-1979, University of Minnesota (Box 27)
    - 1984-1986, with Marschak (Box 27)
    - 1986 (on resource allocations) (Box 28)
    - 1985-1988 (Box 28)
    - 1990s, with Reiter and Richter (Box 28)
    - 2000s, with Richter and Marschak (Box 28)
    - Undated (Box 28)
  - Works by Others, 17 boxes
    Arranged alphabetically. Some folders may contain more than one article or draft.
    - Abramovitz (Box 28)
    - Aguirre Rodriguez (Box 28)
    - Aharoni (Box 28)
    - Afriat (Box 28)
    - Aizpurua (Box 28)
    - Albrecht (Box 28)
    - Aliprantis (Box 28)
    - Allais (Box 28)
    - Amir (Box 28)
    - Anderson, T.W. (Box 28)
    - Antinolofi (Box 28)
    - Aumann (Box 28)
    - Aoki (Box 28)
    - Arrow (Box 28)
    - Arrow (Box 28)
    - Aizpura (Box 28)
    - Aris (Box 28)
    - D'Aspremont (Box 28)
    - Bader (Box 29)
    - Baka (Box 29)
    - Bala (Box 29)
    - Balas (Box 29)
    - Balas (Box 29)
    - Baliga (Box 29)
    - Banks (Box 29)
    - Barbera (Box 29)
    - Bates (Box 29)
    - Baumol (Box 29)
    - Ben-Zion (Box 29)
    - Beckmann (Box 29)
    - Beja (Box 29)
    - Berliant (Box 29)
    - Brenheim (Box 29)
    - Bewley (Box 29)
    - Björklund (Box 29)
    - Blin (Box 29)
    - Bolton (Box 29)
    - Bossaerts (Box 29)
    - Boyd (Box 29)
    - Brahmananda (Box 29)
    - Brams (Box 29)
    - Brandts (Box 29)
    - Brodbeck (Box 29)
    - Burdett (Box 29)
    - Campbell (Box 30)
    - Carlsson (Box 30)
    - Canning (Box 30)
    - Carmona (Box 30)
    - Cass (Box 30)
    - Castillo (Box 30)
    - Carleson (Box 30)
    - Crawford (Box 30)
    - Champlin (PhD dissertation) (Box 30)
    - Chandler (Box 30)
    - Chipman (including his report on the theory of international trade) (Box 30)
    - Cremer (Box 30)
    - Dagan (Box 30)
    - Dahlman (Box 30)
    - Dascupta (Box 30)
    - Dechert (Box 30)
    - Demange (Box 30)
    - Deleau (Box 30)
    - DeGroot (Box 30)
    - Denison (Box 31)
    - Denton (Box 31)
    - Dierker (Box 31)
    - Debreu (Box 31)
    - Diewert (Box 31)
    - Dresher (Box 31)
    - Doede (Box 31)
    - Dubin (Box 31)
    - Dubey (Box 31)
    - Dreze (Box 31)
    - Eaves (Box 31)
    - Eckstein (Box 31)
    - Eliasson (Box 31)
    - El-Gamal (Box 31)
    - Esary (Box 31)
    - Evans (Box 31)
    - Evers (Box 31)
    - Fajnzylber (Box 31)
    - Fan (Box 31)
    - Fand (Box 31)
    - Flood (Box 31)
    - Fox (Box 31)
    - Fuchsteiner (Box 31)
    - Fudenberg (Box 31)
    - Fourgeaud (Box 31)
    - Füredi (Box 31)
    - Futia (Box 31)
    - Gabszewicz (Box 32)
    - Gale (Box 32)
    - Garratt (Box 32)
    - Georgoutsos (Box 32)
    - Gilboa (Box 32)
    - Gjerstad (Box 32)
    - Glazer (Box 32)
    - Gomulka (Box 32)
    - Gottinger (Box 32)
    - Grandmont (Box 32)
    - Granot (Box 32)
    - Green (Box 32)
    - Greenburg (Box 32)
    - Grossman (Box 32)
    - Groves (Box 32)
    - Güth (Box 32)
    - Haavelmo (Theory and Measurement of Economic Relations) (Box 32)
    - Hahn (Box 33)
    - Hammond (Box 33)
    - Halkin (Box 33)
    - Hart, Sergiu (Box 33)
    - Hart, Oliver (Box 33)
    - Harsanyi (Box 33)
    - Hartley (Box 33)
    - Helpman (Box 33)
    - Hoffman (Box 33)
    - Holmstrom (Box 33)
    - Hildreth (Box 33)
    - Hartman (PhD dissertation) (Box 33)
    - Hayashi (Box 33)
    - Hess (PhD Dissertation) (Box 33)
    - Hildebrand (Box 33)
    - Hirschleifer (Box 34)
    - Holmlund (Box 34)
    - Holt, Charles (Box 34)
    - Holt, Robert (Box 34)
    - Hatanaka (Box 34)
    - Indian Economy, 2 reports (Box 34)
    - Inada (Box 34)
    - Ichiishi (Box 34)
    - Jackson (Box 34)
    - Jaffé (Box 34)
    - Jasso (Box 34)
    - Jennergren (Box 34)
    - Johnson (Box 34)
    - Jordan (Box 34)
    - Jorgenson, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Kamiya (Box 35)
    - Kaplan (Box 35)
    - Kelsey (Box 35)
    - Kemp (Box 35)
    - Kiyotaki (Box 35)
    - Klosínski (Box 35)
    - Kochen (Box 35)
    - Koray (Box 35)
    - Konüs (Box 35)
    - Koopmans (Box 35)
    - Krishnaiah (Box 35)
    - Krause (Box 35)
    - Kydland (Box 35)
    - Kurz (Box 35)
    - Kwan (Box 35)
    - Lagunoff (Box 35)
    - Laffont (Box 35)
    - Lal (Box 35)
    - Lang (Box 35)
    - Lau (Box 35)
    - Laub (Box 35)
    - Ledyard (Box 35)
    - Leland (Box 35)
    - Lerner (Box 35)
    - Lloyd (Box 35)
    - Levinthal (Box 35)
    - Lewis (Box 35)
    - Lind (Box 35)
    - Lipnowski (Box 35)
    - Lockwood (Box 35)
    - Lós (Box 35)
    - Lyon (Box 35)
    - Lange (essay on economic planning) (Box 35)
    - Maclane (Box 36)
    - Macminn (Box 36)
    - Majumdar (Box 36)
    - Mandler (Box 36)
    - Manove (Box 36)
    - Margolis (Box 36)
    - Marimon (Box 36)
    - Marshak, Jacob (Box 36)
    - Marschak, Tom (Box 36)
    - Marx, Leslie (Box 36)
    - Mas-Colell (Box 36)
    - Maschler (Box 36)
    - Matsui (Box 36)
    - Matthews (Box 36)
    - McCabe (Box 36)
    - McDonald (Box 36)
    - Montias (Box 36)
    - McAllister (Box 36)
    - Milleron (Box 36)
    - Mount (Box 36)
    - Mookherjee (Box 37)
    - Moore (Box 37)
    - Moiseev (Box 37)
    - Myerson (Box 37)
    - Neuman (Box 37)
    - Newbery (Box 37)
    - Nikaido (Box 37)
    - Nuti (Box 37)
    - Newman (Box 37)
    - Neyman (Box 37)
    - Ok (Box 37)
    - Okuno-Fujiwara (Box 37)
    - Okólski (Box 37)
    - Oniki (Box 37)
    - Osana (Box 37)
    - Oxelheim (Box 37)
    - Page (Box 37)
    - Palfrey (Box 37)
    - Pazner (Box 37)
    - Perkins (Box 37)
    - Plott (Box 37)
    - Pöyhönen (Box 37)
    - Ponti (Box 37)
    - Quirk (Box 37)
    - Radner (Box 38)
    - Reder (Box 38)
    - Reiersøl (Box 38)
    - Richter, Rudolf (Box 38)
    - Richter, M.K. (Box 38)
    - Rees (Box 38)
    - Ruys (Box 38)
    - Reiter (Box 38)
    - Roberts (Box 38)
    - Roemer (Box 38)
    - Rogerson (Box 38)
    - Ross (Box 38)
    - Rose (Box 38)
    - Rubin (Box 39)
    - Rubinstein (Box 39)
    - Rustichini (Box 39)
    - Ruttan (Box 39)
    - Saari (Box 39)
    - Sargeant (Box 39)
    - Sakashita (Box 39)
    - Schofield (Box 39)
    - Schweizer (Box 39)
    - Selton (Box 39)
    - Samuelson, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Satterwhite (Box 39)
    - Shapley (Box 39)
    - Shubik (Box 39)
    - Senesh (Box 40)
    - Serrano (Box 40)
    - Serizawa (Box 40)
    - Simpon (Box 40)
    - Sleszynski (Box 40)
    - Smith (Box 40)
    - Sonnenschein (Box 40)
    - Smale (Box 40)
    - Sumner (Box 40)
    - Suzuki (Box 40)
    - Stiglitz (Box 40)
    - Streutert (Box 40)
    - Suppes, Patrick (Box 40)
    - Tadenuma (Box 40)
    - Tanzi (Box 40)
    - Tesler (Box 40)
    - Thomson, William (Box 40)
    - Thompson, R.G. (Box 40)
    - Tobin (Box 40)
    - Traub (Box 40)
    - Trockel (Box 41)
    - Tuite (Box 41)
    - Uzawa (Box 41)
    - Vega-Redondo (Box 41)
    - Vives (Box 41)
    - U.S. Air Force, 2 reports (Box 41)
    - U.S. Congress (nuclear proliferation, 1977) (Box 41)
    - Varian (Box 41)
    - Vazquez (Box 41)
    - Walker (Box 41)
    - Weitzman (Box 41)
    - Weigend (Box 41)
    - Wiggins (Box 41)
    - Webb, Michael G. (nationalized industries) (Box 41)
    - Williams (Box 41)
    - Wilson, Robert (Box 42)
    - Williamson, Oliver (Box 42)
    - World Bank (report on Poland, 1987) (Box 42)
    - Wooders (Box 42)
    - Wolinsky (Box 42)
    - Yannelis (Box 42)
    - Yoshioka (Box 42)
    - Younés (Box 42)
    - Zabel (Box 42)
    - Zaidi (Box 42)
    - Zajac (Box 42)
    - Zhou (Box 42)
    - Topical Files, 1940s-2006 and undated, 51 boxes
      Includes single subject files, as well as larger groupings of files on Hurwicz's collaborations with Arrow, Marshak, Reiter, Richter, and Saari. These files can contain significant amounts of correspondence. Additional correspondence can be found in the Personal Files and Correspondence Series.
      - Arrow, Kenneth Files 1949-1973, 2 boxes (Box 57)
        - Arrow's paper for PhD graduation, 1949 (Box 57)
        - Gradient Methods and Lagrangian Problems, 1950s (Box 57)
        - Correspondence, 1952-1953, 1957, 1959, 1973 (Box 57)
        - "Programming general spaces" (Box 57)
        - "Selfishness and Decentralization," 1959 (Box 57)
        - Reprints, 1965-1967 (Box 57)
      - Arrow Files (works by or in collaboration with), 1973-1998 (Box 58)
        - On the Dimensional Requirement (Box 58)
        - Comments by Arrow, 1975 (Box 58)
        - Reprints (Box 58)
        - Correspondences, 1978-1982, 1992, 1995, 1998 (Box 58)
        - Undated research materials (one binder) (Box 58)
        - Cauchy (Notes on) (Box 58)
      - China, 1980-1993 (Box 58)
      - China, 1990-2000 (Box 59)
      - Chipman, John (including his collaboration with J. Moore) (Box 59)
      - Coase (theorem)
        - Drafts and notes in relation with "What is the Coase Theorem?", 1993-1995 (Box 60A-60B)
        - The case of two firms, drafts and notes, 1997-2001 (Box 61)
        - Drafts, notes and presentations, 1960-1995 (Box 62)
        - Baumol on the Coase Theorem (externalities) (Box 62)
        - Transparencies and talks, 1995-1999 (Box 63)
      - Cowles Commission and early works, 1940s-1950s (Box 64)
        - Identification in Lagged Shock-Error Models, 1949 (Box 64)
        - "Decision Making under ignorance," 1951 (Box 64)
        - "On the consequence of Incorrect specifications," 1952 (Box 64)
        - "Decentralized Resources allocations," 1954-1955 (Box 64)
      - Debreu, Gérard (Works by and Notes on), 1959-1981 (Box 65)
      - Decentralization
        - Various papers, 1950 (Box 65)
        - Project NSF, 1962 (Box 65)
        - Decentralization, Incentive Structures and Incomplete Information, 1982 (Box 65)